Guide to the Harris Masterson I papers,1860-1942, bulk 1880-1920 MS 468
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series V: Legal Correspondence / Court Documents, 1893-1917 (Boxes 132-189)
  - Harris County Court: Republic Supply Co. v. Robertson (Box 174, Folder 52)
  - Harris County Court: Cage v. Watson (Box 174, Folder 53)
  - Liberty District Court: H. Masterson v. Sylvestor Oppice (Box 175, Folder 1)
  - Bexar Justice Court: Central Trust Co. v. Lubbock (Box 176, Folder 1)
  - Bosque County Court: Bosque Co. v. Allen (Box 176, Folder 2)
  - Criminal cases (Box 176, Folder 3)
  - Brazoria County Court
    - R. G. Gaines v. A. J. Ogburn (Box 176, Folder 4)
    - J. H. Shapard deed to Jas. M. O'Donnell (Box 176, Folder 5)
    - Ed. Young estate (Box 176, Folder 6)
    - W. Cushman estate (Box 176, Folder 7)
    - J. C. Norman estate (Box 176, Folder 8)
    - Allan Larrison estate (Box 176, Folder 9)
    - Jacob Sochn estate (Box 176, Folder 10)
    - W. J. S. B. Moore v. W. Zychlinski (Box 176, Folder 11)
    - Geo. Austin (Box 176, Folder 12)
    - G. B. Jamison estate (Box 176, Folder 13)
    - Preston McBeth estate (Box 176, Folder 14)
    - J. J. Sweeny v. H. L. Trammel (Box 176, Folder 15)
    - John Hanna v. H. Masterson (Box 176, Folder 16)
    - E. M. Harrison estate (Box 176, Folder 17)
    - Levi Jordan estate (Box 176, Folder 18)
    - Abraham Days, deceased (Box 176, Folder 19)
  - Dallas County Court: Preston v. Waggoner (Box 176, Folder 20)
  - Dallas County Court: Masterson v. Alexander (Box 176, Folder 21)
  - Dallas County Court: Jones v. Bonner (Box 176, Folder 22)
  - Falls County Court: McQuary v. St. Paul Fire Marine Insurance Co. (Box 176, Folder 23)
  - Ft. Bend County Court: DeWalt, minors (Box 176, Folder 24)
  - Galveston Justice of the Peace Court: A. H. Belo Co. v. Louis Anti-Waste Cotton Tag Co. et al. (Box 176, Folder 25)
  - Liberty County Court: Teague v. Stevens (Box 176, Folder 26)
  - McLennam Justice of the Peace Court: Griffith v. Walker (Box 176, Folder 27)
  - Midland County Court: Etheridge v. Detroit Fire Marine Insurance Co. (Box 176, Folder 28)
  - Milam County Court: Peter Hall, deceased (Box 176, Folder 29)
  - Nacogdoches County Court: Masterson v. Daniels (Box 176, Folder 30)
  - Travis County Court: Hatzfield v. Allen (Box 176, Folder 31)
  - Harris Justice Court Precinct #1
    - Masterson v. Gibson Kirlicks (Box 177, Folder 1)
    - Cravens Cage v. Campbell (Box 177, Folder 2)
    - Love Kapner v. Masterson (Box 177, Folder 3)
    - Levy Bros. v. Masterson (Box 177, Folder 4)
    - Levy Bros. v. Robertson (Box 177, Folder 5)
    - Cravens Cage v. Jones (Box 177, Folder 6)
    - Pemberton v. Reynolds (Box 177, Folder 7)
    - Haubelt Bros. Henkin (Box 177, Folder 8)
    - Masterson v. Albrecht et al. (Box 177, Folder 9)
    - South Texas Grain Co. v. Converse (Box 177, Folder 10)
    - Masterson v. Lange (Box 177, Folder 11)
    - Williford v. Cage (Box 177, Folder 12)
    - Cage v. Mayes (Box 177, Folder 13)
    - E. Cage v. J. Stewart et al. (Box 177, Folder 14)
    - Williford, Jr. v. Cage (Box 177, Folder 15)
    - Rice v. Bileo (Box 177, Folder 16)
    - Haubelt Bros. v. Cohen (Box 177, Folder 17)
    - Texas Town Lot Improvement Co. v. Brown (Box 177, Folder 18)
    - Beacon Falls Rubber Stone Co. v. Martin (Box 177, Folder 19)
    - Cravens Cage v. DeFee (Box 177, Folder 20)
    - Southern Profit Sharing Co. v. Williams (Box 177, Folder 21)
    - Heitman v. Hudgins (Box 177, Folder 22)
    - Robinson v. Hendricks (Box 177, Folder 23)
    - Harris County Abstract Co. v. Masterson (Box 177, Folder 24)
    - Cravens Cage v. McAllen (Box 177, Folder 25)
    - Cravens Cage v. Bell (Box 177, Folder 26)
    - Cravens Cage v. Clement (Box 177, Folder 27)
    - Cravens Cage v. Wood (Box 177, Folder 28)
    - Cravens Cage v. Stubblefield (Box 177, Folder 29)
    - Cravens Cage v. Christoph (Box 177, Folder 30)
    - Cravens Cage v. Sontag (Box 177, Folder 31)
    - Cravens Cage v. Wills (Box 177, Folder 32)
    - Cravens Cage v. Brown (Box 177, Folder 33)
    - Cravens Cage v. Trott (Box 177, Folder 34)
    - Cravens Cage v. Ellison (Box 177, Folder 35)
    - Downey v. Demsky Co. (Box 177, Folder 36)
    - Masterson v. Pye (Box 177, Folder 37)
    - Harper v. Redmond (Box 177, Folder 38)
    - Holdner v. Chapman (Box 177, Folder 39)
    - Masterson v. Curtis (Box 177, Folder 40)
    - Williams v. Supreme Home of Ancient Order of Pilgrims (Box 177, Folder 41)
    - Masterson v. Curtis (Box 177, Folder 42)
    - Cravens Cage v. Loter (Box 177, Folder 43)
    - Cravens Cage v. Trott (Box 177, Folder 44)
  - Harris Justice Court Precinct #2: Wise v. Murphy (Box 177, Folder 45)
  - Harris Justice Court Precinct #4
    - Haubelt Bros. v. Brown (Box 177, Folder 46)
    - Haubelt v. Mitchell (Box 177, Folder 47)
    - Haubelt Bros. v. Burnstein Roberts (Box 177, Folder 48)
    - Mirck v. Conant Bros. (Box 177, Folder 49)
    - Kirsch v. Osborn (Box 177, Folder 50)
    - Haubelt Bros. v. Riley Bros. (Box 177, Folder 51)
  - Harris County Court
    - B. H. Jenkins v. Allen Masterson (Box 178, Folder 1)
    - Jessie Porter estate (Box 178, Folder 2)
    - Downey Bros. v. W. C. McLaughlin (Box 178, Folder 3)
    - Cravens Cage. v. Woolard Insurance Agency (Box 178, Folder 4)
    - Dwight Belding estate (Box 178, Folder 5)
    - H. F. Pitstick v. T. H. Mimms (Box 178, Folder 6)
    - E. P. Gailey v. S. S. Z. Thompson (Box 178, Folder 7)
    - Texas Louisiana Lumber Co. v. E. M. Haralson (Box 178, Folder 8)
    - J. L. McMahon estate (Box 178, Folder 9)
    - H. Masterson v. H. Lenhart (Box 178, Folder 10)
    - H. Masterson v. J. W. Crow (Box 178, Folder 11)
    - Bay Lumber Co. v. James Black (Box 178, Folder 12)
    - Ida Disney estate (Box 178, Folder 13)
    - H. Masterson v. O. E. Fisher (Box 178, Folder 14)
    - Texas Town Lot Improvement Co. v. A. Sessums (Box 178, Folder 15)
    - N. T. Masterson v. C. L. Hume (Box 178, Folder 16)
    - Girten-Bowman Supply Co. v. Hill Sugar Co. (Box 178, Folder 17)
    - W. H. Coyle estate (Box 178, Folder 18)
    - Central Bank Trust Co. v. W. J. Chambers (Box 178, Folder 19)
    - H. Masterson v. M. Turner (Box 178, Folder 20)
    - Corine N. A. Cline estate (Box 178, Folder 21)
    - Richter Phillips v. M. R. Nichols (Box 178, Folder 22)
    - Cravens Cage v. C. F. Adams (Box 178, Folder 23)
    - C. H. Mayer v. N. T. Masterson (Box 178, Folder 24)
    - Henry Potts v. St. Paul Fire Insurance Co. (Box 178, Folder 25)
    - J. S. Teague v. O'Brien Stevens (Box 178, Folder 26)
    - Cravens Cage v. G. W. Dietz (Box 178, Folder 27)
    - Montgomery Lumber Co. v. N. W. Murphy (Box 178, Folder 28)
    - Wilkes Crosby v. Georgia Crosby (Box 178, Folder 29)
    - H. Masterson v. Galveston, Harrisburg San Antonio Railroad Co. (Box 178, Folder 30)
    - Texas Lumber Co. v. Magnolia Petroleum Co. (Box 178, Folder 31)
    - Laurena Bruner (Box 178, Folder 32)
    - J. O. Ross v. J. W. Danby (Box 178, Folder 33)
    - H. Masterson v. Farmers State Guaranty Bank (Box 178, Folder 34)
    - Nieska Laney v. F. W. Smith (Box 178, Folder 35)
  - United States Circuit Court of Appeals: Fifth Circuit books (Box 179, Folder 1)
  - Court of Civil Appeals for the First Supreme Judicial District of Texas at Galveston books (Box 180, Folder 1)
  - Court of Civil Appeals for various districts books (Box 181, Folder 1)
  - A. B. Coffee, Jr. to H. B. Masterson, July 13, 1923 (Box 182, Folder 1)
  - Mortgage on horse of R. H. Keyworth to N. T. Masterson, September 4, 1914 (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - Release of vendor's lien on property by H. Masterson to Texas Town Lot Improvement Co., January 9, 1914 (Box 182, Folder 3)
  - Release of vendor's lien on property by H. Masterson to Texas Town Lot Improvement Co., November 5, 1914 (Box 182, Folder 4)
  - Partial release from deed of trust by Masterson Irrigation Co. to Rockhill Country Club Co., May 1914 (Box 182, Folder 5)
  - Release on vendor's lien by H. Masterson to Texas Town Lot Improvement Co., June 1914 (Box 182, Folder 6)
  - Transfer of promissory notes with vendor's lien by S. C. Collins to H. Masterson, 1914 (Box 182, Folder 7)
  - Release of vendor's lien on property by Texas Town Lot Improvement Co. to J. H. Dorn, August 27, 1914 (Box 182, Folder 8)
  - Release from vendor's lien on property to George P. Whitbeck by H. Masterson, September 23, 1914 (Box 182, Folder 9)
  - Release from vendor's lien on property to Carmelo Pamilla by Texas Town Lot Improvement Co., September 22, 1914 (Box 182, Folder 10)
  - Release by Jules F. Abadie of warranty on property sold to him by Texas Town Lot Improvement Co., October 1914 (Box 182, Folder 11)
  - Release from three promissory notes and lien to Hattie F. William B. Shephard by N. T. Masterson, January 11, 1915 (Box 182, Folder 12)
  - Release from deed of trust and promissory notes to R. B. Baldwin by N. T. Masterson, January 12, 1915 (Box 182, Folder 13)
  - Release from deed of trust and vendor's lien notes to Charles L. Pierce by Masterson Irrigation Co., June 14, 1915 (Box 182, Folder 14)
  - Release of vendor's lien on note #1 to S. G. Stokes and assignment of notes #2 and #3 to Charles G. Ryan by Masterson Irrigation Co., June 19, 1915 (Box 182, Folder 15)
  - Release of deed of trust to John Love by C. F. Hardin v. N. T. Masterson, October 1915 (Box 182, Folder 16)
  - Release of deed with vendor's lien to Mott Petchnick by Texas Town Lot Improvement Co., February 17, 1915 (Box 182, Folder 17)
  - Release of deed with vendor's lien to A. B. Lorino by Texas Town Lot Improvement Co., September 1914 (Box 182, Folder 18)
  - Receipts of Texas Town Lot Improvement Co. to H. Wilkenfelt for purchase and payment on property, 1913 (Box 182, Folder 19)
  - Receipt to N. T. Masterson for six diamond rings put up by John B. Bleo, February 1, 1913 (Box 182, Folder 20)
  - Contract for purchase of property by G. Gordon through M. Shipira from Texas Town Lot Improvement Co., n.d. (Box 182, Folder 21)
  - Agreement to purchase of property by Alec Byrd, February 24, 1913 (Box 182, Folder 22)
  - Receipt of Texas Town Lot Improvement Co. to H. Wolf A. H. Albert and contract for purchase of property, n.d. (Box 182, Folder 23)
  - Substitution of N. T. Masterson for A. R. Masterson in the deed of trust of John Morgan to the Texas Town Lot Improvement Co., October 7, 1915 (Box 182, Folder 24)
  - Loan agreement between Dave Elizabeth Dugas and N. T. Masterson, January 1914 (Box 182, Folder 25)
  - Contract between R. B. Baldwin N. T. Masterson re: option to buy mortgage property, January 1917 (Box 182, Folder 26)
  - Sale of interest in judgment of AETNA Life Insurance Co. to N. T. Masterson, February 13, 1910 (Box 182, Folder 27)
  - Deeds and papers re: purchase of property by J. D. Jackson, C. M. Jackson, Ida J. Rudisill through the Houston Town Lot Improvement Co., April 14, 1905 (Box 182, Folder 28)
  - Promissory note of C. R. Miller to Houston Town Lot Improvement Co. for purchase of land and construction of house, 1903-1911 (Box 182, Folder 29)
  - Statements to Mrs. Bethe Bryan from various oil companies, 1908 (Box 182, Folder 30)
  - Deed of trust between Ike Miles N. T. Masterson, agent for the Houston Town Lot Improvement Co., September 21, 1915 (Box 182, Folder 31)
  - Deed of trust from Joe Misnarich to N. T. Masterson, trustee of the Masterson Irrigation Co., 1911 (Box 182, Folder 32)
  - Assignment of notes of John C. Mahoney to H. Masterson, agent for Masterson Irrigation Co. by L. Bryan Co., April 27, 1912 (Box 182, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence re: mortgage made by the Texas Town Lot Improvement Co. to Farmers Bankers Warehouse Building Corp., 1906-1908 (Box 182, Folder 34)
  - Assignment of vendor's lien to N. T. Masterson and the Texas Town Lot Improvement Co. by M. Shapiro, April 17, 1913 (Box 182, Folder 35)
  - Deed of trust by Joe Levy to N. T. Masterson, agent of Texas Town Lot Improvement Co., April 24, 1913 (Box 182, Folder 36)
  - Inventory of property of A. E. Masterson for assessment of taxes in Harris County, 1909 (Box 182, Folder 37)
  - Agreement between L. A. Lamber and N. T. Masterson re: payment of defaulted notes, August 10, 1910 (Box 182, Folder 38)
  - Deed of trust between Thomas W. Matthews, Jr. and N. T. Masterson, November 8, 1915 (Box 182, Folder 39)
  - Deed of trust from William McKinnon to Elliot Cage for benefit and use of N. T. Masterson, July 10, 1918 (Box 182, Folder 40)
  - Writ of injuction against J. E. Winfree, N. T. Masterson, T. N. Jones, January 30, 1919 (Box 182, Folder 41)
  - Petitions and documents re: appeal on writ of error for James A. Black v. Bay Lumber Co. filed by Elliot Cage, 1914-1915 (Box 182, Folder 42)
  - Oil pipe line agreements between Elliot Rowena Cage and various pipeline companies, 1921 (Box 182, Folder 43)
  - Warranty deed with vendor's lien of Frank Mary Watson to William Alice Sennett, October 18, 1902 (Box 182, Folder 44)
  - Certified copy of last will of Mary Elizabeth Elgin, June 4, 1908 (Box 182, Folder 45)
  - Appointment by Michael Daly of Asa Hickman, to act as his agent, July 24, 1884 (Box 182, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence and legal papers re: Texas and vendor's lien on land of David Cohen, 1908-1909 (Box 182, Folder 47)
  - Note with vendor's lien of J. M. Morris for loan from L. M. Disney, 1894 (Box 182, Folder 48)
  - Note of Richard G. Maury for collection, April 19, 1912 (Box 182, Folder 49)
  - Promissory notes of E. W. Lemon to H. R. Atkin, August 31, 1909 (Box 182, Folder 50)
  - Promissory notes with vendor's lien from H. W. Lawrence and L. M. Disney, March 1894 (Box 182, Folder 51)
  - Indenture for the partition of land made by W. S. Margaret Griffin, Agne D. S. Killough, and H. W. Atkinson, 1910 (Box 182, Folder 52)
  - Contract between John Millinger and C. L. Berney re: improvements on property on Risk St., June 12, 1914 (Box 182, Folder 53)
  - Deed of trust between Munger Land Co. Alfred N. Goss, January 29, 1921 (Box 182, Folder 54)
  - Deed of trust from Bettie Wilson Thomas to G. W. Thomas, November 22, 1894 (Box 182, Folder 55)
  - Foreclosure and sale of property of F. Z. Bishop to Mrs. L. J. Masterson, July 7, 1921 (Box 182, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence from J. V. Abrahams to Cora Weaver re: Knights Ladies of Security, 1916 (Box 182, Folder 57)
  - Reconveyance of notes from E. Roberts to H. Masterson by F. F. Chew, November 1913 (Box 182, Folder 58)
  - Duplicate copy of receipt for note given as retainer against possible claims by heirs of Nancy Rendon, September 8, 1883 (Box 182, Folder 59)
  - Contract between Joseph Stohl and Elliot Cage re: agreement with R. B. Rogers to sell his son's tract of land, 1903 (Box 182, Folder 60)
  - Transfer of vendor's lien notes on land in Coleman County from Walter Washburn to H. Masterson, July 27, 1897 (Box 182, Folder 61)
  - William W. Dudley to Mrs. Emilie Irgang, October 10, 1892 (Box 182, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence of Elliot Cage, 1892-1906 (Box 182, Folder 63)
  - F. A. Hornaday to E. E. Guthrie re: stock and debts of Texas Motor Car Co., 1910 (Box 182, Folder 64)
  - Correspondence with McLain Orthopedic Sanitarium re: son of Mrs. Kaytie Coyle, 1915 (Box 182, Folder 65)
  - Bill of sale of automobile by Jack Saunders to Al Brooks, February 14, 1919 (Box 182, Folder 66)
  - Copies of by-laws, probably Masterson Irrigation Co. Texas Town Lot Improvement Co., n.d. (Box 183, Folder 1)
  - Statements of by-laws of Texas Town Lot Improvement Co. Masterson Irrigation Co. re. acquisition and sale of property, 1910-1911. (Box 183, Folder 2)
  - Abstract and title to property in Port Arthur sold to the Wolnitzck, 1902-1905 (Box 183, Folder 3)
  - Sale of vendor's lien votes of Payne's Chapel African Methodist Episcopal Church to H. Masterson, 1907-1910 (Box 183, Folder 4)
  - Papers re. the Standard Auto Co., 1910-1911 (Box 183, Folder 5)
  - Articles of Incorporation of Gulf Land Lumber Co., 1906 (Box 183, Folder 6)
  - Agreement for incorporation on H. H. Everest Co., 1905 (Box 183, Folder 7)
  - Agreement to incorporate Masterson Land Co., 1906 (Box 183, Folder 8)
  - Papers of agreements and formation of Yankton Railroad Co., 1907 (Box 183, Folder 9)
  - Article of incorporation of the Raney Oil Co., 1908 (Box 183, Folder 10)
  - Agreement for incorporation of the Houston Loan Co., 1910 (Box 183, Folder 11)
  - Agreement for incorporation of the Houston Livestock Co., 1910 (Box 183, Folder 12)
  - Agreements to incorporate and from the Harris Land Co., 1910 (Box 183, Folder 13)
  - Papers and minutes of board of directors Harlingen Land Water Co., 1913-1915 (Box 183, Folder 14)
  - Papers of Cotton Mills Securities Co., 1913 (Box 183, Folder 15)
  - Resolution of board of directors of Hill Sugar Co., 1914 (Box 183, Folder 16)
  - Papers of the Lon C. Hill Town Improvement Co., 1913 (Box 183, Folder 17)
  - Notices of stockholders meetings, minutes, and correspondence of Port Houston Land Townsite Co., 1909-1916 (Box 183, Folder 18)
  - Minutes and resolutions of the Houston Town Lot Improvement Co., 1913 (Box 183, Folder 19)
  - Affidavits re. payment of promissory notes by S.H. Kress Co. to H. Masterson, 1914 (Box 183, Folder 20)
  - Marriage license of Joseph W. Johnston Mary Jackson, 1889 (Box 183, Folder 21)
  - Lists of debts owed H. Masterson lands owed in Brazoria Harris counties, 1912 (Box 183, Folder 22)
  - Oath of intention to pass deed from George Walker to A. Block, January 17, 1910 (Box 183, Folder 23)
  - Claims against estate of Bonnie Faye Nettie Dunlavy and reports, 1898 (Box 183, Folder 24)
  - Authorities on remedies to over assessment of tax on property, n.d. (Box 183, Folder 25)
  - Copies of articles of agreement re. corporation to take over pursuit of claims in Mexico, May 1, 1914 (Box 183, Folder 26)
  - Bill of sale of two diamonds to H. Masterson, January 16, 1913 (Box 183, Folder 27)
  - Resolution minutes and sale of interest to H. Masterson of Masters Motion Picture Co., July 31, 1917 (Box 183, Folder 28)
  - Specification for building of store and residence for Harry J. Carrie Jefferies, May 8, 1905 (Box 183, Folder 29)
  - Receipt of H. Masterson to Brockman Kahn for rent of Alamo Hotel for holding until settlement of McSweeney v. Ellerman, September 16, 1908 (Box 183, Folder 30)
  - Receipt to H. Masterson for money from estate of Irene Brown, September 28, 1916 (Box 183, Folder 31)
  - Notes re. duty of husband to support wife, n.d. (Box 183, Folder 32)
  - Receipt of Joe H. Eagle for cancelled note from H. Masterson, April 3, 1913 (Box 183, Folder 33)
  - Receipt of Houston Abstract Co. for titles delivered to H. Masterson, June 20, 1913 (Box 183, Folder 34)
  - Receipt of H. Masterson for abstracts for examination in resale of vendor's lien notes, May 23, 1914 (Box 183, Folder 35)
  - Various unsigned promissory notes arranged through the office of H. Masterson, 1913-1914 (Box 183, Folder 36)
  - By-laws of the Lon C. Hill Town Improvement Co., n.d. (Box 183, Folder 37)
  - By-laws of Southern Land Livestock Co., December 15, 1906 (Box 183, Folder 38)
  - Assignment of collectable fees to H. Masterson by C. N. Nelson, Sheriff of Brazoria County, November 17, 1887 (Box 184, Folder 1)
  - Certificate of incorporation of Brazoria Construction Co., 1889 (Box 184, Folder 2)
  - Bill of sale of 700 head of cattle by Abe Holt to H. Masterson, 1889 (Box 184, Folder 3)
  - Agreement between county representatives and A. H. Williams re. grading road, August 10, 1892 (Box 184, Folder 4)
  - Agreement for disposition of steamboat Naomi and settlement of accounts, February 10, 1898 (Box 184, Folder 5)
  - Agreements between O. D. Quinn H. Masterson re. road grading contracts, March 29, 1898 (Box 184, Folder 6)
  - Assignment of payment due by P. H. Rogers to H. Masterson, April 20, 1893 (Box 184, Folder 7)
  - Copy of charter of Lubricant Oil Refining Co., May 1898 (Box 184, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence re. Masonic Lodges, 1898-1911 (Box 184, Folder 9)
  - Sale of option to buy olive mine by R. H. Downmen et al. to H. Masterson J. S. Dougherty, March 25, 1903 (Box 184, Folder 10)
  - Sale of notes with vendor's lien by T. S. Jarrel to H. Masterson, April 8, 1904 (Box 184, Folder 11)
  - Notes and papers re. loan to John Murphy by H. Masterson, 1904-1905 (Box 184, Folder 12)
  - W. D. Tuper to H. Masterson re. sale of Cunningham Sugar Plantation, 1905 (Box 184, Folder 13)
  - Note of payment with vendor's lien, 1905 (Box 184, Folder 14)
  - Documents re. a loan made to J. B. Brockman by H. Masterson and its repayment, 1905-1906 (Box 184, Folder 15)
  - Papers and notes re. loan made to Jno. Lyons by H. Masterson, 1905-1911 (Box 184, Folder 16)
  - Loan agreement between E. H. Ricker H. Masterson and collateral put up to secure the loan, 1907 (Box 184, Folder 17)
  - J. S. Duff to H. Masterson re. sale of notes of Leesville Leader, August 29, 1910 (Box 184, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence re. suit of James Ingolls v. J. M. Reagan et al., December 19-20, 1910 (Box 184, Folder 19)
  - Documents re. purchase of notes of A. M. Osborne by H. Masterson from F. E. Pye, 1910 (Box 184, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence and legal papers in suit – S. M. Johnson v. H. Masterson, 1910 (Box 184, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence and petitions re. sale and repossession of automobile by H. Masterson to F. E. Pye, 1910-1912 (Box 184, Folder 22)
  - Note sold to H. Masterson by Andrew Dow for T. H. Mims, January 6, 1911 (Box 184, Folder 23)
  - Contract between J. J. Sweeney H. Masterson re. sale of notes, March 9, 1911 (Box 184, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence and legal papers re. release of employee's liens, 1911 (Box 184, Folder 25)
  - Assignment of insurance policy to H. Masterson for collection by H. L. Mims, 1911 (Box 184, Folder 26)
  - Promissory note of W. A. McClure to H. Masterson, December 20, 1912 (Box 184, Folder 27)
  - Bill of sale of Diebold Safe by H. Masterson to Marine Park Amusement Co., 1912 (Box 184, Folder 28)
  - Memorandum re. Masterson position in suit of Andrew J. Wilson v. H. Masterson, December 16, 1912 (Box 184, Folder 29)
  - Assignment of vendor's lien by J. M. Harvard to H. Masterson, February 23, 1913 (Box 184, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence to C. R. Wharton to Coke K. Burns re. Shelp Rubber Supply Co., 1914 (Box 184, Folder 31)
  - Officer for sale of notes to Max Krost by H. Masterson, 1915 (Box 184, Folder 32)
  - Promissory note of A. C. Allen Cooper Merrill, endorsed to H. Masterson, April 9, 1919 (Box 184, Folder 33)
  - Lease agreement between Masterson Irrigation Co. S. P. Martin re. land for cultivation, April 7, 1917 (Box 185, Folder 1)
  - Earnest agreement for sale of property of South Dakota Texas Oil Co. to A. R. Kinney et al., March 30, 1917 (Box 185, Folder 2)
  - Contract agreement between Masterson Irrigation Co. B. H. Christian Co. re. liabilities in use of spur track through land of first party, May 1917 (Box 185, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum of agreement between Masterson Irrigation Co. John W. Maxey re. building of fence between property, May 30, 1917 (Box 185, Folder 4)
  - Receivers bond posted by N. T. Masterson as the principal H. Masterson as surety, n.d. (Box 185, Folder 5)
  - Deed of trust of A. B. Pickett to N. T. Masterson for use of R. H. Keyworth, May 1914 (Box 185, Folder 6)
  - Incomplete deed of trust of Marlon F. Kirkpatrick to N. T. Masterson, n.d. (Box 185, Folder 7)
  - Deed of trust and note of Mountain Townside Co. to N. T. Masterson, June 27, 1914 (Box 185, Folder 8)
  - Incomplete deed of trust to N. T. Masterson for use of Texas Town Lot Improvement Co., June 1914 (Box 185, Folder 9)
  - Deed of trust and note of Clifford Greve to N. T. Masterson for use of S. L. Hartburt, July 20, 1914 (Box 185, Folder 10)
  - Deed of trust and note of John Love to N. T. Masterson for use of C. E. Hardin, December 17, 1914 (Box 185, Folder 11)